Bienen, Leigh B.; Papers apap312
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Reference Materials, 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated; 5; 8.2 cubic ft.
  - Capital Punishment: Developments 1961 to 1965, 1967 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Emanuel Tanay, "Psychiatric Study of Homicide", 1969 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Philip M. Hauser, "The Census of 1970", 1971 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Royal Commission on Capital Punishment 1949-1953 Report, 1973 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Ralph Slovenko, Tragicomedy in Court Opinions, 1973 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Charles W. Wolfram, "The Constitutional History of the Seventh Amendment", 1973 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Jurek v. Texas, 1975 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - Woodson v. North Carolina, 1975 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Deborah Denno articles and letter, 1976 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Austin Sarat and Neil Vidmar, "Public Opinion, The Death Penalty, and the Eighth Amendment: Testing the Marshall Hypothesis", 1976 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Articles by R. Emerson Dobash and Russell P. Dobash, 1977 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Victoria Lynn Swigert and Ronald A. Farrell, "Normal Homicides and the Law", 1977 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Elliot S. Valenstein, Report on Psycho surgery, 1977 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Rupert V. Barry, "Furman to Gregg: The Judicial and Legislative History", 1978 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - Jennifer James, "The Prostitute as Victim", 1978 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - "A Ten Year Follow - up of Sex Offender Recidivism, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - Amnesty International - "Proposal for a Presidential Commission on the Death Penalty in the United States of America", 1980 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Walter Berns, "Defending the Death Penalty", 1980 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Arthur L. Stinchcombe, et. al., Crime and Punishment - Changing Attitudes in America, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - David C. Baldus, et. al., "The Differential Treatment of White and Black Victim Homicide Cases In Georgia's Capital Charging and Sentencing Process: Preliminary Findings, 1982 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - "Capital Losses: The Price of the Death Penalty for the New York State ", 1982 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - F. Patrick Hubbard, Brenton G. Burry and Robert Widener, "A 'Meaningful' Basis for the Death Penalty: The Practice, Constitutionality, and Justice of Capital Punishment in South Carolina", 1982 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - National Center for State Courts Research Model for Determining Death Penalty Costs, ca.1982 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - "Overcrowded Time: Why Prisons are so Crowded and what can be Done", 1982 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - Centers for Disease Control Homicide Surveillance Reports, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - Janine Jason et. Al., "Homicide as a Cause of Pediatric Mortality in the United States", 1983 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - Irwin I. Kimmelman, "The Death Penalty in New Jersey," New Jersey Lawyer, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Tichnell v. Maryland, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - James E. Lobsenz, "Unbridled Prosecutorial Discretion and Standardless Death Penalty Policies: The Unconstitutionality of the Washington Capital Punishment Statutory Scheme", 1984 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - Beverly Martinez - Schnell and Richard J. Waxweiler, "Increases in Premature Mortality Due to Homicide - United States, 1968-1985", 1989 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - McCleskey v. Kemp, 1984 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Patrick W. O'Carroll and James A. Mercy "Regional Variation in Homicide Rates: Why is the west so Violent?", 1989 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Prejean v. Blackburn, 1989 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Research on Death Penalty costs, ca. 1989; 1988; Undated (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - Richard Van Duizend, "Comparative Proportionality Review in Death Sentence Cases", 1984 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Ralph Weisheit, "Female Homicide Offenders: Trends over time in an Institutionalized Population", 1984 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - James R. Acker, "Mandatory Capital Punishment for the Life Term Inmate who Commits Murder: Judgment of Fact and Value in Law and Social Science", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Ursula Bentele, "The Death Penalty in Georgia: Still Arbitrary", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 44)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 45)
  - Margot Garey, "The Cost of Taking a Life: Dollars and Sense of the Death Penalty", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 46)
  - Darnell F. Hawkins and Kenneth A. Hardy, "Black - White Imprisonment Rates: A State - by - State Analysis", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 47)
  - Nature of crime makes exception to Death Row rule, 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 48)
  - Michael L. Radelet, "Rejecting the Jury: The Imposition of the Death Penalty in Florida", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 49)
  - Mark L. Rosenberg and James A. Mercy, "Homicide: Epidemiologic Analysis at the National Level", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 50)
  - Gregory Stein, "Distinguishing Among Murders When Assessing the Proportionality of the Death Penalty", 1985 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 51)
  - Amnesty International - USA Death Penalty Briefing, ca. 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 52)
  - Articles by Ann Goetting on Homicide among females and wives, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 53)
  - Dennis Balske and James G. O'Haver, "Death Penalty Training Manual", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 54)
  - John S. Carroll, et. al., "Free Press and Fair Trial: The Role of Behavioral Research", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 55)
  - Centers for Disease control Homicide Surveillance Report, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 56)
  - McCleskey v. Kemp - Syllabus, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 57)
  - James A. Mercy et. al., "Patterns of Homicide Victimization in the City of Los Angeles, 1970-79", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 58)
  - Patrick W. O'Carroll and James A. Mercy "Homicide Among Black Americans", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 59)
  - Nancy Pennington and Reid Hastie, "Evidence Evaluation in Complex Decision Making", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 60)
  - State v. Palmer, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 61)
  - Peter Meijes Tiersma, "Dictionaries and Death: Do Capital Jurors understand Mitigation?", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 62)
  - University of New Hampshire Family Research Laboratory, ca. 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 63)
  - Ralph A. Weisheit, "When Mothers Kill Their Children", 1986 (Box 1 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 64)
  - Amnesty International - United States of America, The Death Penalty, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Articles by Peter David Blanck, 1987; 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - Susan Bandes, "Southern California Law Review - Taking some Rights too seriously: The State's Right to a Fair Trial", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Hugo Adam Bedau and Michael L. Radlet, "Miscarriages of Justice in Potentially Capital Cases", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - Lisa Gayle Bradley, "Proportionality in Capital and Non-Capital Sentencing: An Eighth Amendment Enigma", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Caseload and Cost Projections for Habeas Corpus Death Penalty Cases in fiscal years 1998 and 1989, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Centers for Disease Control - Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Pat Doherty and Kevin McNally, "Confronting the Question of the Victim's Family: Before, During and After Trial", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Thomas Havlena, "Abolishing the Death Penalty - Why? How? When?", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Report to the Deputy Attorney General on Capital Punishment and the Sentencing Commission, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Lawrence T. White, "Juror Decision Making in the Capital Penalty Trial", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Brian Wiersema and Karen Kindley, "An Attribute Approach to Homicide Classification", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - William Wilbanks, "Reactions to McCleskey vs. Georgia", 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Margo Wilson and Martin Daly, Articles on Spousal Homicide, gendered culture, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Leslie Abramson and Andrea Lyon, "Control of the Courtroom at Trial", 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Bureau of Justice Statistics - Murder in Large Urban Counties, 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Jacqueline Cook, "Coming Full Circle: A Return to Arbitrary Sentencing Patterns in Capital Punishment Cases", 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Mary Elizabeth Holland, "McClesky v. Kemp: Racism and the Death Penalty", 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Kansas Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - Longitudinal Court Outcome Study of Individuals Accused of Homicide Reported in 1988, 1993 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - McDowell Juror Questionnaire, ca. 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Margaret Vandiver, Capital Punishment in America: An Annotated Biography, 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Margaret Vandiver, Capital Punishment in America: An Annotated Biography, 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Gennaro F. Vito and Thomas J. Keil, "Capital Sentencing in Kentucky: An Analysis of the Factors Influencing Decision Making in the post - Gregg period" (pre-publication), 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - Gennaro F. Vito and Deborah G. Wilson "Back From the Dead: Tracking the Progress of Kentucky's Furman - Commuted Death Row Population", 1988 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - James R. Acker and Elizabeth R. Walsh, "Challenging the Death Penalty Under State Constitutions", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - James R. Acker, "The Grand Jury and Capital Punishment: Rethinking the Role of an Ancient Institution Under the Modern Jurisprudence of Death", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - James R. Acker, "Thirty Years of Social Science in Supreme Court Criminal Cases", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - Jonathan D. Casper, Kennette Benedict, and Jo L. Perry, "Juror Decision Making, Attitudes, and the Hindsight Bias", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - Federal Death Penalty Act of 1989, Racial Justice Act of 1994 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - Herb Haines, "Primum Non Nocere: Chemical Execution and the Limits of Medical social Control", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Jury Comprehension in Complex Cases, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - Stephen P. Klein, Allan F. Abrahamse, and John E. Rolph, "Relationship of Offender and Victim Race to Death Penalty Sentences in California", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - Memorandum in Opposition to S.600/A.1070, New York Lawyers Against the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - New Jersey Supreme Court Task Force on Minority Concerns - Interim report, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Greg Newbold, "Capital Punishment in New Zealand: An Experiment that Failed", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Non-Statutory Mitigating Circumstances, 1989 January 4 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Daniel Okada and Arnold Raimondo, "The Incarcerated Vietnam Vet: Preliminary Investigations on the Vietnam Veteran and the Criminal Justice System, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - Ben F. Overton, "Trial Judges and Political Elections: A Time for Re-Examination", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Raymond Paternoster and AnnMarie Kazyaka, "An Examination of Comparatively Excessive Death Sentences in South Carolina 1979-1987", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - D. Michael Risinger, et. al., "Exorcism of Ignorance as a Proxy for Rational Knowledge: The Lessons of Handwriting Identification 'Expertise' ", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Sawyer v. Smith - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 44)
  - Shari Seidman Diamond, Jonathan D. Casper and Lynne Ostergren, "Blindfolding the Jury", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 45)
  - Silagy v. Peters III, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 46)
  - Statement of Ronald J. Tabak on behalf of the American Bar Association before the Committee on the Judiciary of the United States Senate on Racial Discrimination and the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 47)
  - Testimony of Julius L. Chambers concerning the Racial Justice Ace of 1988, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 48)
  - Neil J. Vidmar, "Empirical Research and the Issues of Jury Competence, 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 49)
  - Neil J. Vidmar and Regina A. Schuller, "Juries and Expert Evidence: Social Framework Testimony", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 50)
  - Hans Zeisel and Alec M. Gallup, "Death Penalty Sentiment in the United States", 1989 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 51)
  - American Bar Association support for H.R. 4737 Habeas Corpus Revision Act of 1990 and "Fatal Defense " The National Law Journal (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 52)
  - American Journal of Public Health, "The Prevalence of Severe Mental Disorder among male urban Jail Detainees", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 53)
  - Capital Report - Death Penalty Litigation Section, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 54)
  - Census of State and Federal Correctional Facilities, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 55)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 56)
  - Correctional Populations in the United States, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 57)
  - William J. Curran, "The Ethics of Medical Participation in Capital Punishment by Intravenous Drug Injection", 1980 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 58)
  - "Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities", Report to Senate and House committees on the Judiciary, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 59)
  - General Accounting Office Report to Senate and House Committees on the Judiciary - "Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 60)
  - Governor's Management Review Commission, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 61)
  - Lawrence A. Greenfeld, "Capital Punishment 1990", Bureau of Justice Statistics Bulletin, ca. 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 62)
  - David A. Kaplan and Lauren Picker "The Executioner's Handyman", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 63)
  - James Luginbuhl, "Successfully Challenging the Highly Pro - Death Juror", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 64)
  - Walter F. Murphy and Joseph Tanenhaus, "Publicity, Public Opinion, and the Court", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 65)
  - Laura B. Myers, "Prosecutorial and Judicial Decision - Making: A Contextual Comparison of Charging and Sentencing Decisions", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 66)
  - Silagy v. Warden, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 67)
  - Tom W. Smith, "Liberal and Conservative Trends in the United States Since World War II", 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 68)
  - Statement of Randall M. Dana, National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers before the Subcommittee on Crime, U.S. House Judiciary Committee, 1990 (Box 2 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 69)
  - Ronald Tabak, "Execution of Injustice: Under Any Test, Death Penalty Fails", 1990 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Ronald J. Tabak, "Review of Law & Social Change", 1990 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - United Nations Social Development - Capital Punishment, 1990 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - United States General Accounting Office Report to Senate and House Committee on the Judiciary - Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities, 1990 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - Amendment to House of Representatives Bill 3371 - Equal Justice Act, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - American Criminal Law Review, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - The American University Law Review, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Amnesty International - The Death Penalty List of Abolitionist and Retentionist Countries, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Articles by Craig Haney, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Mark Ballard, "Judges Clogging Death - Penalty Docket; Harris DA's Study finds Half of Cases Await Decisions", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Michael Booth, "Kwiatkowski convicted in ex-wife's strangling, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - William J. Bowers and Margaret Vandiver, "New Yorkers want an Alternative to the Death Penalty", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - David I. Bruck, "Does the Death Penalty Matter? Reflections of a Death Row Lawyer", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Leigh Dingerson, "Reclaiming the Gavel: Making Sense Out of the Death Penalty Debate in State Legislatures", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Easy Access - version 1.0, National Center for Juvenile Justice, 1991 (Floppy-disk 3)
  - Gallup Poll, "Death Penalty Support Remains Strong, But Most Feel Unfairly Applied", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Valerie P. Hans and Neil Vidmar, "The American Jury at Twenty-Five Years", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Harmelin v. Michigan, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Rhonda G. Hartman, "Critiquing Pennsylvania's Comparative proportionality Review in Capital Cases", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Robert A. Harvie, "Where Is The Man? The Search for a Juvenile court in Montana", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - House of Representatives Bill HR.2851, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - House of Representatives Bill 2851 - Fairness in Death Sentencing Act, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - Wayne King, "Defiant Widow Seeks to Reopen Lindbergh case", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Bruce Ledewitz, "Sources of Injustice in Death Penalty Practice: The Pennsylvania Experience", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Mark Mauer, "Americans Behind Bars: A Comparison of International Rates of Incarceration", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - Carrie Menkel-Meadow and Shari Seidman Diamond, "The Content, Method, and Epistemology of Gender in Sociolegal Studies", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - Lori L. Nader, "Walton v. Arizona: the Confusion Surrounding the Sentencing of Capital Defendants Continues", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - Nalini K. Pande, "The Death Penalty and the Mentally Retarded Defendant; Diminished Culpability and Inadequate safeguards", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Glenn L. Pierce, "Florida Law Review, Choosing Those Who Will Die: Race and the Death Penalty in Florida", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - Michael L. Radelet and Glenn L. Pierce, "Florida Law Review: Choosing Those Who Will Die: Race and the Death Penalty in Florida", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - Recap: Capital Litigation, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - Statement of John J. Curtin, Jr. and James S. Liebman concerning Fairness and Efficiency in Habeas Corpus Adjudication, 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - Heather Strong, "Homicides in Australia" (with letter), 1991; 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Ronald J. Tabak, "Justice Brennan and the Death Penalty", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - Ronald J. Tabak and J. Mark Lane, "Albany Law Review: Judicial Activism and Legislative 'Reform' of Federal Habeas Corpus: A Critical Analysis of Recent Developments and Current Proposals", 1991 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - ABA Journal, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - Articles on Proportionality Review from Deborah W. Denno, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Bureau of Justice Statistics Special Report, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Drucilla Cornell, "Gender, Sen and Equivalent rights", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Shari Seidman Diamond, Jonathan D. Casper, "Blindfolding the Jury to Verdict Consequences: Damages, Experts, and the Civil Jury", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - Florida State University Law Review, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Lonny J. Hoffman, "The Madness of the Method: The Use of Electrocution and the Death Penalty", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - Lifelines, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Lifelines, No. 56, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 44)
  - Mental Retardation and Physician Aid-in-Dying, 1992; 1997 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 45)
  - Otey v. State of Nebraska - Brief and position papers, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 46)
  - "Prosecutor v. Scientist: A Cat-and-Mouse Relationship", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 47)
  - Michael R. Rand "The Study of Homicide Caseflow: Creating a Comprehensive Homicide Dataset", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 48)
  - Michael J. Saks and Peter David Blanck, "Justice Improved: The Unrecognized Benefits of Aggregation and Sampling in the Trial of Mass Torts", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 49)
  - Socio - Legal Bulletin, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 50)
  - U.S. Department of Justice Statistics - Capital Punishment 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 51)
  - Margo I. Wilson and Martin Daly, "Who Kills Whom in Spouse Killings? On the Exceptional Sex Ratio of Spousal Homicides in the United States", 1992 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 52)
  - Alabama Death Penalty cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 53)
  - Arizona Death Penalty Cases, ca. 1993 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 54)
  - Ursula Bentele, "Race and Capital Punishment in the United States and South Africa", 1993 (Box 3 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 55)